Guide to the Edith Wharton Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Professional Correspondence, 1905-37; Series III; 4; (9 boxes)
  - D. Appleton and Co., 1935-37 (Box 36, Folder 1078-84)
  - Darby, Lucy, 1919-20 (Box 36, Folder 1085)
  - The Delineator, 1926-19 (Box 36, Folder 1086)
  - Dodd, Mead and Co., 1920-27 (Box 36, Folder 1087)
  - "E" general, 1919-34 (Box 36, Folder 1088)
  - Edel, Leon, 1928-35 (Box 36, Folder 1089)
  - Empire Theater
    See Charles Frohman, Inc., Box 32, folder 997
  - Eric S. Pinker and Adrienne Morrison, Inc., 1934-37 (Box 36, Folder 1090-91)
  - Espasa-Calpe, S. A., 1930 (Box 36, Folder 1092)
  - "F" general, 1919-37 (Box 36, Folder 1093-94)
  - Faber and Faber, 1929-31 (Box 36, Folder 1095)
  - Férard (Maison L. Férard), 1927-28 (Box 36, Folder 1096)
  - Le Figaro, 1929-36 (Box 36, Folder 1097)
  - Flammarion (Les Librairies Flammarion), 1928-37 (Box 36, Folder 1098)
  - The Forum, 1923-28 (Box 36, Folder 1099)
  - Frederick A. Stokes, 1927-36 (Box 36, Folder 1100)
  - Franzos, Marie, 1930-31 (Box 36, Folder 1101)
  - "G" general, 1917-36 (Box 36, Folder 1102-03)
  - Gallimard (Librairie Gallimard), 1923, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 1104)
  - Gerson, Virginia, 1918-20 (Box 36, Folder 1105)
  - Librairie Giraud-Badin, 1928-29 (Box 36, Folder 1106)
  - Gitterman, Joseph L., 1922, 1929 (Box 36, Folder 1107)
  - Grant, John, 1933-36 (Box 36, Folder 1108)
  - "H" general, 1919-37 (Box 37, Folder 1109-10)
  - Hachette (Librairie Hachette), 1923-27, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1111)
  - Herbert, Dolly, 1925-30 (Box 37, Folder 1112)
  - "I" general, 1924-25 (Box 37, Folder 1113)
  - Incorporated Society of Authors, Playwrights, and Composers, 1927-36 (Box 37, Folder 1114)
  - International Mark Twain Society (Cyril Clemens), 1927-36 (Box 37, Folder 1115)
  - "J" general, 1920-36 (Box 37, Folder 1116)
  - Jewett, Rutger B.
  - John Charpentier, 1919-36 (Box 37, Folder 1117)
  - John and Edward Bumpus, Ltd., 1926-27 (Box 37, Folder 1118)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood
    See: American Academy of Arts and Letters, Box 31, folder 957
  - Jonathan Cape, Ltd., 1922-36 (Box 37, Folder 1119-21)
  - "K" general, 1923-32 (Box 37, Folder 1122)
  - Kauser, Alice, 1935-37 (Box 37, Folder 1123-28)
    See also: Mary Cadwalader Jones, Box 28, folders 836-62
  - "L" general, 1918-37 (Box 37, Folder 1129-30)
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1931-33 (Box 37, Folder 1131)
  - Lavaux, A., 1920-36 (Box 37, Folder 1132-36)
  - League of American Pen Women, 1925-28 (Box 37, Folder 1137)
  - Lechevalier, Jacques Lechevalier, Paul, 1926-27 (Box 37, Folder 1138)
  - Life and Letters, 1928-34 (Box 37, Folder 1139)
  - The Literary Review, 1920-25 (Box 37, Folder 1140)
  - Lowe Brothers, Ltd., 1936-37 (Box 37, Folder 1141)
  - "M" general, 1917-36 (Box 37, Folder 1142-43)
  - Macmillan and Co., 1905-30 (Box 38, Folder 1144-47)
  - Madeleva, M., 1934, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1148)
  - Martineau, Alice, 1925-29 (Box 38, Folder 1149)
  - The Medici Society, 1924-33 (Box 38, Folder 1150)
  - Miles, James, 1922-30 (Box 38, Folder 1151)
  - Morrison, Adrienne
    See: Eric S. Pinker and Adrienne Morrison, Inc., Box 36, folder 1090
  - Moss Empires (Howard Wyndham Tours), 1935-36 (Box 38, Folder 1152)
  - "N" general, 1922-35 (Box 38, Folder 1153)
  - National Council of Women of the United States, Inc., 1933 (Box 38, Folder 1154)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1926-36 (Box 38, Folder 1155)
  - The New York Times, 1916 Jan 9 (Box 38, Folder 1156)
  - Nieuwe Rotterdamsche Courant, 1918-20 (Box 38, Folder 1157)
  - "O" general, 1920-36 (Box 38, Folder 1158)
  - Oxford University Press, 1932-36 (Box 38, Folder 1159)
  - "P" general, 1918-35 (Box 38, Folder 1160-61)
  - Perrin and Cie (Librairie Academique Didier), 1927-30 (Box 38, Folder 1162)
  - Peyser, Ethel R., 1924-25 (Box 38, Folder 1163)
  - Pfeffer, Max, 1935-36 (Box 38, Folder 1164)
  - Pinker, Eric
  - Plon-Nourrit (Librairie Plon-Nourrit), 1920-37 (Box 38, Folder 1165-69)
  - Pugh, Cynthia Ann, 1930-31 (Box 38, Folder 1170)
  - Quarterly Review, 1920-32 (Box 38, Folder 1171)
  - Quereuil, J. A. (L'Office Bibliographique), 1923-34 (Box 38, Folder 1172)
  - Quinn, Arthur Hobson, 1937 (Box 38, Folder 1173)
  - "R" general, 1917-37 (Box 38, Folder 1174-75)
  - Reynolds, Paul R., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 1176)
  - La Revue de France, 1917-35 (Box 38, Folder 1177-78)
  - Revue des Deux Mondes, 1918-38 (Box 39, Folder 1179-80)
  - La Revue de Paris, 1917-26 (Box 39, Folder 1181)
  - La Revue Hebdomadaire, 1917-37 (Box 39, Folder 1182)
  - Royal Society of Literature, 1929-35 (Box 39, Folder 1183)
  - Rumbold, Zoë Akins, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1184)
  - "S" general, 1917-37 (Box 39, Folder 1185-86)
  - Sandry-Schmitt, Susan, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1187)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1918-19 (Box 39, Folder 1188)
  - The Saturday Review, 1924-34 (Box 39, Folder 1189)
  - Schneider and Amelag, 1928-32 (Box 39, Folder 1190)
  - Sheldon, Edward, 1927-34 (Box 39, Folder 1191)
    See also: Box 30, folder 923
  - Simon and Schuster, 1935-36 (Box 39, Folder 1192)
  - Smith and Earle, 1926 (Box 39, Folder 1193)
  - Steedman, Robert D., 1931-32 (Box 39, Folder 1194)
  - "T" general, 1925-37 (Box 39, Folder 1195)
  - The Times (London), 1920-36 (Box 39, Folder 1196)
  - Toomy, Mary, 1932-34 (Box 39, Folder 1197)
  - Universitaire, Librairie (J. Gamber), 1925-31 (Box 39, Folder 1198)
  - "V" general, 1919-36 (Box 39, Folder 1199)
  - Van Doren, Carl, 1934 (Box 39, Folder 1200)
  - Vidakovic, A., 1927-29 (Box 39, Folder 1201)
  - Vogue, 1926-27 (Box 39, Folder 1202)
  - "W" general, 1921-37 (Box 39, Folder 1203-04)
  - The Yale Review, 1919-30 (Box 39, Folder 1205-06)
  - "Z" general, 1926-33 (Box 39, Folder 1207)
  - Unidentified, 1921-37, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1208-09)
- General Correspondence, 1901-37; Series IV; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  Series IV, General Correspondence, is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 40, Folder 1210)
  - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 40, Folder 1211)
  - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 40, Folder 1212-16)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 40, Folder 1217-21)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 40, Folder 1222-30)
  - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 1231-39)
  - Correspondence, 1921 Jan-Jun (Box 41, Folder 1240-48)
  - Correspondence, 1921 Jul-Dec (Box 42, Folder 1249-53)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 42, Folder 1254-67)
  - Correspondence, 1923 Jan-Sep (Box 42, Folder 1268-80)
  - Correspondence, 1923 Oct-Dec (Box 43, Folder 1281-85)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 1286-1305)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Jan-Mar (Box 43, Folder 1306-11)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Apr (Box 44, Folder 1312-21)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 1322-33)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 44, Folder 1334-46)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 45, Folder 1347-61)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 45, Folder 1362-81)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 1382-97)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 1398-1412)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 47, Folder 1413-25)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 1426-42)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 1443-56)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Jan-Jul (Box 48, Folder 1457-65)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Aug-Dec (Box 49, Folder 1466-71)
  - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 1472-88)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 1489-97)
- Personal Papers, Dates 1910-37; Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Personal Papers, is divided alphabetically into subject files.
  - Account books and notes
    - The Age of Innocence (Mary Cadwalader Jones), 1929 (Box 50, Folder 1498)
    - Equitable Trust Company, 1915 (Box 50, Folder 1499)
  - Addresses, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1500)
  - Biographical sketches, 1937, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1501)
  - Books: inventory (at "Jean-Marie"), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1502)
  - Clippings (collected by Edith Wharton), 1914-29, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1503-04)
  - Composition exercise in Italian (holograph), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1505)
  - Contracts
    - D. Appleton-Century, 1912-34 (Box 50, Folder 1506-08)
    - Macmillan and Co., 1906, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 1509)
    - Scribner's, 1900-25 (Box 50, Folder 1510-11)
    - Dramatizations, 1924-36 (Box 50, Folder 1512-13)
    - Foreign publishers, 1906-19 (Box 50, Folder 1514)
  - Copyrights, 1922-28 (Box 50, Folder 1515)
  - Currency, French, 1915, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1516)
  - Decorations and honors: announcements and documentations
    - French Legion of Honor, 1916, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1517)
      See also: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1836
    - Miscellaneous French and Belgian Awards (Box 50, Folder 1518)
      See also: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1837
    - Honorary Yale degree, 1923 (Box 50, Folder 1519-20)
    - Pulitzer Prize certificate
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1838
  - Diaries, 1905-34 (Box 51, Folder 1521-23)
  - "Edith Wharton Tells of German Trail of Ruin" (newspaper article), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1524)
  - "Education Through the Eyes" (newspaper article), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1525)
  - Gardens
    - Plans (St. Claire, Pavillion Colombe), n.d. (Box 68 (Broadside)–69 (Broadside))
    - Plant lists, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1527-28)
  - Identification papers, permits (World War I), 1914-18 (Box 51, Folder 1529)
  - "More Money Needed" (letter to the Daily News, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1530)
  - Empty Folder (Box 51, Folder 1531)
  - "My Work Among the Workers of Paris" (newspaper article), 1915 Nov 28
  - Notes: "Jibares of Ecuador", n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1532)
  - Obituaries, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 1533-34)
  - "Osprey" notes and accounts (Yacht), [1926] (Box 51, Folder 1535-37)
  - Permits, automobile (World War I), 1915-18 (Box 51, Folder 1538)
  - Publications lists, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1539)
  - The Reader, vol. III, no. 1, 1928 Apr (Box 51, Folder 1540)
  - Recipe for "Christmas Pudding", n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1541)
  - Royalty Statements
    - General account book, 1904-14 (Box 52, Folder 1542)
    - The Century Company, 1910-33 (Box 52, Folder 1543)
    - D. Appleton, 1913-30 (Box 52, Folder 1544)
    - Macmillan and Co., 1906-18 (Box 52, Folder 1545-46)
    - Scribner's, 1906-29 (Box 52, Folder 1547)
      See also: Charles Frohman, Inc. Box 32, folder 997
  - Ste. Claire Chateau (Hyèrs)
    - House plans, 1909 (Box 52, Folder 1548)
    - Title, 1927 (Box 52, Folder 1549)
  - Settembrini, History of Italian Literature (copy of "The Reformation" section in Edith Wharton's hand) (Box 52, Folder 1550)
  - "The Theaters" (Wharton's review of Tess of the D'Urbervilles ), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1551)
  - War charities (Box 52, Folder 1552-66)
    See also: Box 38, folder 1156
  - Wharton, Edward (letters concerning his health), 1909-11 (Box 52, Folder 1567)
  - Miscellaneous, 1917, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1568-70)
- Photographs, Dates 1868-1930; Series VI; 7.5; (5 boxes)
  Series VI, Photographs, is subdivided into nine subseries: (1) Edith Wharton, (2) Group Pictures: Edith Wharton with relatives and friends, (3) Other People, (4)Homes, (5) War Charities, (6)Related Photos, (7) Postcards, (8) Unidentified, and (9) Duplicates. The subseries Edith Wharton is arranged chronologically; the subseries Homes is arranged chronologically by date of residence; the subseries Other People is arranged alphabetically.
  - Edith Wharton, c. 1868-1930 (Box 53, Folder 1571-88)
    See also: Oversize, Box 67, folders 1839-41
  - Group Pictures: Edith Wharton with friends and relatives, 1901, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1589-1601)
  - Other People
    - Austin, Mary [Great great grandmother]
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1842
    - Berry, Walter, c. 1905 (Box 54, Folder 1602-03)
    - Bourget, Paul, [1923] (Box 54, Folder 1604)
    - Cornell, Katharine, 1928 (Box 54, Folder 1605)
    - Doyle, Hannah, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1606)
    - Farrand, Beatrix (and unidentified others) (Box 54, Folder 1607)
    - Gross, Catherine (Edith Wharton's housekeeper), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1608)
    - James, Henry: Charcoal sketch by John Singer Sargent
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1843
    - Jones, George Edward (and Lucretia Jones), 1881, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1609)
    - Jones, Henry (and Lucretia Stevens) (Box 54, Folder 1610)
    - Lodge, George Cabot, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1611)
    - Lyauty, Herbert, 1917 (Box 54, Folder 1612)
    - Norton, Robert (and Howard Sturgis), 1936 (Box 54, Folder 1613)
    - Rhinelander, Frederick (copy of photograph) (Box 54, Folder 1614)
    - Stevens, Ebenezer [Great grandfather]
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1844
    - Stevens, Mrs. [Great grandmother]
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1845
    - Tyler, Elisina Royall, c. 1910 (Box 54, Folder 1615)
    - Wharton, Edward, 1896 (Box 54, Folder 1616-17)
      See also: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1846
    - [Edith Wharton's great great grandmother] (Box 54a, Folder 1618)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 1619-22)
  - Homes
    - West 25th St., New York, N. Y., n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 1623)
    - Pencraig Cottage, Newport, R. I., n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 1624-25)
    - Park Avenue, New York, N. Y., n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 1626)
    - "The Mount"
      - Grounds and gardens (Box 54b, Folder 1626a-c)
      - See also: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1847
      - Interiors, n.d. (Box 54b, Folder 1626d-e)
      - "Land's End," Newport, R. I. (also Lamb House and Queen's Acre) (Box 54b, Folder 1627-29)
      - "Reef Point," Bar Harbor, Maine, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1630)
      - "Hopewell Green," West Dover, Vt., n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1631)
      - "Pavillion Colombe," St. Brice sous Foret, France, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1632-42)
      - "Ste. Claire" (Hyères), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1643-51)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1652-53)
  - War Charities
    - American Hostels for Refugees (Arromanches, Normandy) (Box 56, Folder 1654)
    - American Hostels for Refugees (Groslay), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1655)
    - Children of Flanders (Box 56, Folder 1656-57)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1658-59)
  - Related Photographs
    - Edith Wharton exhibition, [1962] (Box 56, Folder 1660)
    - Edith Wharton's dogs, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1661-62)
    - Gravesite of Mary Cadwalader Jones, 1935 (Box 56, Folder 1663)
    - Leoube Picnic, 1936 (Box 56, Folder 1664-65)
    - "Osprey", 1926 (Box 56, Folder 1666)
  - Postcards (Oberammergau and miscellaneous travel) (Box 56, Folder 1667-68)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1669-70)
  - Duplicates, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1671-72)
- Gaillard Lapsley Material, 1895-1939; Series VII; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series VII, Gaillard Lapsley Material, is arranged alphabetically by surname.
  - Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1907-25 (Box 57, Folder 1673-79)
  - Gardner, Isabella (Stewart), 1895-1900 (Box 57, Folder 1680-83)
  - Lubbock, Percy, 1908-11 (Box 57, Folder 1684-85)
  - Lubbock, Percy, 1912-33 (Box 58, Folder 1686-1700)
  - Lubbock, Percy, 1934-39, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1701-02)
  - Poole, Reginald Lane, 1918 Jan 9 (Box 59, Folder 1703)
  - Sturgis, Howard O., 1912 Sep 8 (Box 59, Folder 1704)
  - Wharton, Edith, 1895-1925 (Box 59, Folder 1705-15)
  - Wharton, Edith, 1926-37 (Box 60, Folder 1716-31)
- Oscar Lichtenberg Material, 1900-27; Series VIII; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series VIII, Oscar Lichtenberg Material, consists primarily of alphabetically arranged correspondence. Page proofs for "Autre Temps" are located in the last folder.
  - Gale, Zona, 1902 (Box 61, Folder 1732)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1902-09, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1733)
  - Harris, Gordon L. (to Mary Cadwalader Jones), 1927 May 26 (Box 61, Folder 1734)
  - Holman, Miss, 1916 (Box 61, Folder 1735)
  - Howells, William D., 1902 May 26 (Box 61, Folder 1736)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1911, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1737-38)
  - Lichtenberg, Oscar H., 1918, 1927 (Box 61, Folder 1739)
  - Mitchell, S. Weir, [1902] (Box 61, Folder 1740)
  - Munro, D. A., 1902 May 24 (Box 61, Folder 1741)
  - Parrish, Maxfield (to Robert V. Johnson), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1742)
  - Unidentified, 1927 May 5 (Box 61, Folder 1743)
  - "Autres Temps" page proofs, typed, corrected (by Mary C. Jones), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1744)
- Percy Lubbock Material, Date: 1939; Series IX; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Reminiscences of Edith Wharton (original letters and manuscripts, holographs and typescripts), 1939, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1745-49)
  - Reminiscences of Edith Wharton, with list of contributors. Typescript draft by Percy Lubbock, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1750-56)
- Georges Markow-Totevy Material, 1915-52; Series X; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series X, Georges Markow-Totevy Material, is divided into four subseries: (1) Correspondence (2) Notes (3) Copies of Wharton's Works and (4) Other Papers. Within each subseries, arrangement is alphabetical by surname or title.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Letters to Edith Wharton
      - Berenson, Bernard, 1936 May 27 (Box 63, Folder 1757)
      - Bourget, Paul (to Edith Wharton?), 1932 Feb 16 (Box 63, Folder 1758)
      - James, Henry (copy, typescript), 1912 Dec 4 (Box 63, Folder 1759)
      - Paget, Violet ("Vernon Lee"), 1932 May 7 (Box 63, Folder 1760)
      - Miscellaneous (copies: extracts), 1901-37 (Box 63, Folder 1761)
    - Letters to Georges Markow-Totevy
      - Bibesco, Princesse (photocopy), 1952 (Box 63, Folder 1762)
      - Casteja, Garrison, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1763)
      - Chanler, Margaret, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 1764)
      - Cocteau, Jean (photocopy), 1952 Feb 10 (Box 63, Folder 1765)
      - D'Asenberg, E., 1951 Nov 8 (Box 63, Folder 1766)
      - De Reginer, Marie, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 1767)
      - La Forest-Divonne, Levis-Mirepoir, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 1768)
      - Noufflard, B. A., 1951 Oct 9 (Box 63, Folder 1769)
      - Romains, Jules (photocopy), 1952 Feb 4 (Box 63, Folder 1770)
      - Tyler, Elisina Royall, 1952 Mar 30 (Box 63, Folder 1771)
  - NOTES
    - The Book of the Homeless, etc., n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1772)
    - "Guerre", n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1773)
    - Horoscope of Edith Wharton, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1774)
    - Interviews, 1951, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1775)
    - Last Journal of Edith Wharton, 1936-37 (extracts), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1776)
    - Last Words of Edith Wharton (by Elisina Royall Tyler), n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1777)
    - "Livres de Notes d'E.W.", n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1778)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1779-80)
  - COPIES OF EDITH WHARTON'S WORKS
    - Fast and Loose (with review) (Box 63, Folder 1781)
    - "Ogrin the Hermit", n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1782)
    - "Penelope", n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1783)
    - "Treasure", n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1784)
    - Untitled poem, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1785)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Obituaries, 1937 (Box 63, Folder 1786)
    - Photographs and negatives (Box 63, Folder 1787)
    - Tyler, Elisina Royall. "Introduction à la Connaissance de la Méthode de Radio Photographie." (Fondation Edith Wharton) (Box 63, Folder 1788)
    - Valmyre, Alexandre. "Médecine Officielle, Médecine Radiesthesiste" (Box 63, Folder 1789)
  - Notes and transcriptions made by Georges Markow-Totevy, 2017 April 24-25 (Box 63, Folder 1789a)
- Louis Auchincloss Material, 1881-1938; Series XI; 3; (2 boxes)
  Series XI, Louis Auchincloss Material, is divided into six spiral bound books, with letters and other material generally chronologically arranged.
  - Letters, 1881-1924 (Box 64, Folder 1790-92)
  - Letters, 1925-38 (Box 65, Folder 1793-95)
- Other Papers, 1873-1981; Series XII; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series XII, Other Papers, is arranged alphabetically by author, title, or subject.
  - Berry, Walter. Obituaries, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1796)
  - Biographies of Edith Wharton: Reviews, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1797)
  - Bourget, Minnie, Untitled sonnet. Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1798)
  - Boynton, H. W. "The Novels of Edith Wharton." The New York Evening Post, 1913 Oct 24 (Box 66, Folder 1799)
  - "Bulletin of the National League of American Pen Women", 1923 Mar (Box 66, Folder 1800)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, "Edith Wharton", 1937 Aug (Box 66, Folder 1801)
  - Crowninshield, Frank. "Newport... Those Days, This War", n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1802)
  - Sturgis, Howard Overing. "Dialects," with drawings, [1873?] (Box 66, Folder 1803)
  - "The Early Edith Wharton." The Times Literary Supplement, 1953 Mar 20 (Box 66, Folder 1804)
  - "The Edith Wharton Collection." (Yale University), n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1805)
  - Edith Wharton Commemorative Stamp
    - Stamps, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1806)
    - Plate blocks
      See: Oversize, Box 67, folder 1848
    - Reproductions, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1807)
    - Poster, 1980
      See: Oversize, folder 1849
    - Press kit, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1808)
    - Commemorative stamp ceremony (letters and related material), 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1809)
    - First day covers, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1810)
    - First day cover (gift of Bradbury Thompson, with program and clipping), 1980 (Box 66, Folder 1810a)
  - [Edwards, Harry Stillwell]. Untitled newspaper article on Edwards, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1811)
  - "The Essence of Life" Humanities, Vol. VII, no. 4, 1977 May (Box 66, Folder 1812)
  - Follett, Wilson. "What Edith Wharton Did - and Might Have Done." The New York Times Book Review, 1937 May (Box 66, Folder 1813)
  - Friends' Intelligencer, 1913 Jul 5 (Box 66, Folder 1814)
  - Gay, Walter. Obituaries, 1937 (Box 66, Folder 1815)
  - Goldberger, Paul. "Edith Wharton Home: An Unusual Rescue." The New York Times, 1980 Aug 7 (Box 66, Folder 1816)
  - Goldberger, Paul. "To Be Lived In." The New York Times Magazine, 1979 Sep 30 (Box 66, Folder 1817)
  - Gillet, Louis. "Walter Gay.", n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1818)
  - Greenwood, Joan Voss. "Importance of Milieu in Edith Wharton's Short Stories and Novellas." Studies (Kobe College) Vol. 5, no. 2, 1958 Oct (Box 66, Folder 1819)
  - Herrick, Robert. "Mrs. Wharton's World" The New Republic, 1915 Feb 15 (Box 66, Folder 1820)
  - James, Henry: Last Will and Testament, 1916 (Box 66, Folder 1821)
  - La Farge, John. "Sifa Dancing the Sitting Siva" (Illustration for La Farge's Reminiscences of the South Seas, photographic reproduction of drawing) Gift of Gaillard Lapsley, n.d.
    See: Oversize, folder 1850
  - Letter opener given by Edith Wharton to Walter Berry, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1821a)
  - Lewis, R. W. B. "Edith Wharton: The Beckoning Quarry." American Heritage, Vol. XXXVI, no. 6, 1975 Oct (Box 66, Folder 1822)
  - Lewis, R. W. B. Edith Wharton: A Biography. Reviews, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 1823)
  - Lewis, R. W. B. "Powers of Darkness." Times Literary Supplement, 1975 Jan 13 (Box 66, Folder 1824)
  - Maarek, ---. Portrait of Walter van Rensselaer Berry (oil on canvas, 22.25" x 22"), n.d.
    See: Oversize, folder 1851
  - Le Petit Parisien (Armistice Proposal), 1918 Oct 6 (Box 66, Folder 1825)
  - Pamphlets, miscellaneous, 1923, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1826)
  - Reed, Henry Hope, Jr. "Edith Wharton's Brownstone World." New York Herald Tribune Sunday Magazine, 1962 Nov 4 (Box 66, Folder 1827)
  - Sasaki, Miyoko. "Between Appearance and Substance: Study of Edith Wharton." Studies in American Literature, No. 11, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 1828)
  - Sencourt, Robert. "Edith Wharton." The Cornhill Magazine, vol. 157, no. 942, 1938 Jun (Box 66, Folder 1829)
  - "Situation in Edith Wharton", n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1830)
  - "A Television Portrait of Edith Wharton." Humanities, vol. 2, no. 5, 1981 Oct (Box 66, Folder 1831)
  - "Turn of the Century Society: R. W. B. Lewis to Lead Seminar." The Leading Dock, vol. 4, no. 3, 1976 Mar (Box 66, Folder 1832)
  - Writings About Edith Wharton (miscellaneous), 1964, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1833)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1968-75, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1834-35)
- Oversize, 1900-80; 2; (1 box)
  - French Legion of Honor (Ordre National de la Légion D'Honneur), 1923 (Box 67, Folder 1836)
  - Diploma from Societe Nationale d'Horticulture de France, 1923 (Folder 1837 (broadside))
  - Pulitzer Prize certificate, 1921 (Folder 1838 (broadside))